Oscar Osorio

Software Engineer

Email: oosoriod@my.centennialcollege.ca

Career Summary

Oscar is a self-motivated and creative software engineer with 4+ years of experience providing effective software solutions for different industries Strong educational background in software architecture (full software development life cycle, design patterns, agile methodologies, frameworks, and development tools). Good professional communication skills, ability to handle varying workloads and aptitude for teamwork.

MongoDB

Education

Francisco Jose de Caldas University, Bogota, Colombia

Jul. 2015 – Jul. 2016

BS, Software Engineering Specialist

Summary of Qualifications

Skills:

- Web services .Net Core JavaScript .Net (REST, WCF) Scrum MVC SOL server Framework Angular .Net Platform SQL Server Entity React Integration Node Js Service framework
- Languages

C#

•Spanish (native speaker) •English (advanced)

HTML5/CSS3

Career History

GLOBANT, Bogotá, Colombia

Sep. 2020 – Present

Semi senior software developer

- Researching, designing and developing software components.
- Implementation of testing units, debugging, diagnosing and correcting errors and faults.
- Writing, maintaining and deployment of software solutions based on quality standards.
- Migrating, automating, enhancing, and simplifying system process and applications.

LINEXPERTS, Bogotá, Colombia

Jan. 2019 – Mar. 2020

Senior software developer

- Researching, designing and developing software components.
- Implementation of testing units, debugging, diagnosing and correcting errors and faults.
- Writing, maintaining and deployment of software solutions based on quality standards.
- Providing advice, guidance and expertise in developing proposals and strategies for software design activities.
- Writing, updating and maintaining end user documentation and operational procedures.

PERIFERIA IT GROUP, Bogotá, Colombia

Jan. 2016 - Sep. 2017

Software developer

- Researching, consulting, designing and developing software components.
- Analysis and troubleshooting.
- Writing, maintaining and deployment of software solutions in accordance with quality accredited standards.
- Writing, updating and maintaining technical program, end user documentation and operational procedures.

Git

• Azure

CI\CD